The fish is very fresh today
今天的烤子鱼特别新鲜
Eat up, enjoy yourself
你们别客气，多吃点
Sorry to interrupt your dinner
不好意思，打扰你们吃饭
Never mind, let's sit over there
不要紧，我们过那边坐
It's quite late
怎么这样晚？
I've just finished work
是啊，刚下班
What should I call you?
怎么称呼你
You can call me Mrs. Suen
叫我孙太太
And you?
你呢？
My husband's name is Chan
我先生姓陈
Call me when you decide I will
- 决定了就给我电话 - 好的
Did you write down my number?
有没有把号码抄下
Yes, I did
抄下了
Fine, I'll see you out
那好，我送你出去
Don't trouble No trouble
- 不用了 - 要的，大家上海人嘛
So it's agreed then
那么就这样决定了
Thank you very much, I should go
谢谢你，我先走了
Fine Bye
- 好的 - 再见
Take care, goodbye
慢走，再会
You've a room to let?
请问这里是不是有房间出租？
Sorry, it's just been rented to that lady
真对不起，刚租给那位太太
Thanks
谢谢你
How many of you?
你几个人住？
Just me and my wife
我跟我太太两个人
Why don't you try next door
你不妨到隔壁试试看
They've a vacant room too?
隔壁有房间出租吗？
Yes, Mr.Koo's son got married
是，隔壁顾先生的儿子刚结婚
and removed out
搬了出去
His room's empty
房间也想找人租
Thank you
谢谢你
You're too polite, Try asking them
不客气，你尽管试试
Thank you
谢谢
This way, come on
来，这里
Not that room
这个不是我们的
Wrong again
怎么搞的，真麻烦
Careful, against the wall there
先靠墙放着，小心啊
The little cupboard over there
小柜子靠在那边
Be careful
慢慢来
Don't break anything
小心，别碰坏别人的东西
Not on top of the radio
别压坏了收音机
Mr.Chow
周先生
You have a lot of stuff for a couple
怎么家俱这样多？
The wardrobe isn't mine, wrong again?
- 这个柜不是我的 - 又搬错？
It does next door
是不是隔壁的？
Okay, next door
那搬回去，搬回去
There aren't my shoes
这些鞋子不是我的，是不是拿错了
They must go next door
我想是隔壁的，拿过去吧
What a coincidence, moving in on same day
真是巧，搬家都碰在一起
Is Mr.Chan here?
怎么没看见你先生？
He's working abroad
公司有事派他出门了
He'll be back next week
下礼拜才回来
You should have waited, then
那你该等他回来再搬嘛
It's too much for you on your own
搬家那么辛苦，你一个人应付得了吗？
I can manage I'll ask Amah to help
- 我可以的 - 叫王妈帮忙
No need, I can manage
别客气，孙太太，我自己行的
What's going on?
怎么回事？
Mind that mirror
小心那镜子
Mrs. Chan, I'll leave you to it
陈太太，你继续收拾好了
Those books aren't mine Wrong again?
- 这些书不是我的 - 又错了？
Never mind, just leave them there
不要紧，先放下吧
Mind how you hang the mirror it's fragile
这个小心放，这些会砸烂的
Are these magazines yours?
这些杂志是不是你的？
Yes, they're my husband's
是的，我先生的
He reads Japanese?
你先生懂日文啊？
A little, his boss is Japanese
懂一点，他老板是日本人
How should I address you?
还没请教你贵姓？
My husband's name is Chan
我先生姓陈
My name's Chow... I'll leave you in peace
我姓周，我先回去了
Thank you, Mr.Chow
谢谢你周先生
Don't mention it
不客气
I'll ask Mrs. Chan...
我去叫陈太太
Mrs. Chan, eat with us before you go
陈太太，跟我们一起吃饭吧
No thanks, I must dash to the airport
我不吃了，我赶时间，我得去机场
Your husband's coming back? Yes
- 你先生回来了？ - 是的
Then I won't keep you
那我不耽误你了
Going out? Yes
- 出去呀？ - 晚安
Sorry, I'm late
对不起，我迟了
Amah, pour some beer
王妈，快点倒酒
Cheers
干杯
Mrs. Chow, try some Shanghai dishes
- 周太太，尝一尝我们的上海家常菜 - 我自己来就行了
Where is Mrs. Chan to so late?
陈太太到哪里去了？
Meeting here husband at the airport
她去接飞机嘛，她先生回来了
So that's why she looks different
怪不得打扮得那么漂亮
It's all packed, take care on your trip
我都帮你收拾好了，你自己小心点
I will
知道了
How long this time?
你这回去好久吗？带那么多东西？
Two to four weeks
是呀，要一两个月
Remember when you come back
你记得回来的时候
Bring back two more of those handbags
带两个你上回送给我的皮包
Who for?
谁要？
Mr.Boss
我老板
Two of them?
两个那么多？
You know why
你知道啦
Different colours?
那要不要同颜色？
The same will do? Who cares?
一样颜色行了，管它呢
Whatever
呐，可是你说的
Mrs. Ho
何太太吗？我是苏秘书呀
Mr.Ho is still in a meeting
何先生现在还在谈事情
He'll be home late
他说今晚会晚回家
Please don't wait to eat
叫你们别等他吃饭
Yes, we're so busy at the moment
是啊，我们这阵子很忙
Yes, I'll ask him to call you when he gets back
我请他忙完了给你打电话
Did you call my wife?
给我太太打过电话了？
Yes, I said you'd be back later
打过了，我说你会晚一点回去
Have you booked the restaurant?
帮我订了位没有？
A table for two at eight
订了，八点两位
Miss Yu called to say
余小姐刚来电话，她说马上要出门
she's on her way
叫你快点
I'll be back after dinner
吃过饭我就回来
can I bring you something?
要不要带点东西给你吃
No thanks, I'll get my own
不客气，我自己出去吃就行了
Leave when you're ready
如果你办完事情我还没回来
I'll lock up
你先走，我来锁门好了
Good evening, Mr.Ho Evening
何先生，你走了？
Going out, Mrs. Chan Yes
- 陈太太，出去呀？ - 是的
Going out so late?
这时候还要出去呀？
Just getting some noodles
我去买面
Amah is making pork soup, join us
王妈在弄蹄膀汤，大家一块吃
Thanks, I'm not really hungry I just want some air
别客气，我不是太饿，我想出去走走
You're too polite Next time
- 不要客气嘛 - 下次吧
They're all starving, we can eat
王妈，三哥他们都饿了，我们吃吧
Have you spoken to Ming?
跟明哥说了没有？
So I'll go with someone else
那么我跟别人去
Just kidding
讲着玩的
I'll be early tonight, see you soon
我会早点下班，你也早点回来
Bye
- 再见 - 再见
Chow
阿周
Coming
来啦
Time to go, finish it tomorrow
周，下班了，东西留着明天做
No, I'm nearly there
做的差不多了，弄完再走了
Oh, Ming
明哥
I need a few days off next month why?
- 我下个月想请几天假 - 干什么？
I promised my wife a trip
答应跟太太去旅行，都说了好几年
Put in a word for me, will you?
你帮帮我
I'll speak to personnel
好吧，我跟人事部讲讲
But the next lunch is on you
不过，你可要请吃饭
I'll
怎样都行
Thanks, Ming
多谢你明哥
It's ready
好了，好了
No, it'll switch itself off
还没呢，饭熟了那个键会跳起来
I told you, it's not ready
哪有这么快，你这乡下人
A rice cooker, It's yours, Mrs. Koo?
电饭锅啊，新买的，顾太太？
No, it's beyond us
像我们这些老古板
It's Mrs. Chan's
哪晓得买这种东西，是陈太太的
My husband brought it from Japan
我先生从日本带回来的
I wanted to show Mrs. Koo how good it is
我看挺好，所以介绍给顾太太
Now it's ready
跳起来了，跳起来了
It's workable, you can see
这回真行了，你看多方便
Mrs. Chan
陈太太
Could Mr.Chan get me one next time?
麻烦你陈先生，下次帮我带一个回来
No problem
好，没问题
Mr.Chow, you should get one too
周先生，你也应该买上一个
Your wife's so often late home
你太太老是值夜班，有了它就方便多了
I couldn't trouble Mr.Chan
麻烦陈先生不太好意思
It's just neighborly, isn't it?
隔壁邻居，无所谓啦
It's no trouble
不要紧，他过两天会再去
I'll ask him to buy another next time
我叫他多带一个回来
Thank you
那么多谢你了
Let's try the rice
来，我们尝尝
Mr.Chan, sorry to trouble you about the rice cooker
真不好意思，要你老远带电饭锅给我
It was really no trouble
顺手的嘛，用不着客气
How much do I owe you?
还没付钱你，该多少钱？
Your wife has already paid me
你太太已经给我了
Really?
是吗？
She didn't tell you?
她没告诉你？
She's been working late shifts
她这阵子值夜班
Often I'm asleep when she gets back
等她回来我已经睡了
It must be hard for her
在酒店做事也真辛苦
Yes
是啊
Mrs. Chan isn't back yet?
陈太太还没回来？
She'll be back soon, you need to talk to her
我想她快回来了，你有事找她？
A friend needs to go to Singapore
我有个朋友过两天去新加坡
I wonder if she could get a cheap ticket for him
想看看陈太太的公司有没有 便宜点的船票
I'll ask when she gets back
等她回来我告诉她
I'm bothering you too much
麻烦你们不好意思
Don't mention it, we're neighbors
客什么气，大家隔壁邻居，应该的
I'll leave you in peace
那么我先回去了
Looking for me?
怎么，找我？
Damn right, where've you been?
打着锣找呢，整个上午到哪儿去了？
What's up?
什么事呀？
Mrs. Chan called
陈太太打电话来
you left a hat at her office
说你把帽子忘在她公司了
I meant to, I wanted an excuse to go back
我故意的，不然哪有机会多看她两眼
I know your tricks
早知你会来这一手
she's married
人家可是有老公的
I know
我当然知道她有老公
That's why I left
要不我还回来干嘛
otherwise I'd move in next door
干脆搬到你那儿去
If your wife wasn't so attractive
说真的，幸好你老婆也是美人
She'd be a worried woman
要不然我可要替她担心
I'm not like you
你当我是你啊
Please call Mrs. Chan for me
帮我打电话约陈太太
I'll pick up the hat tomorrow
说我明天上她公司拿帽子
And take her to lunch
顺便请她喝茶
Dream on, I asked her to
你想得美
take the hat home
我跟她说了，把帽子先拿回家
I'll bring it in tomorrow
明早我帮你带回来
You're kidding, some buddy you are
真泄气，还是老朋友呢
Tell you what, let's go pick up now
索性我跟你回家去
She should be off work by now
这个钟点应该下班了
We can go together
一块儿接她下班去
I don't have time for this
懒得跟你讲
Chow
阿周
Yes, get out of here, I'm busy
来啦，快走吧，我还要忙
Then I'll wait at your place
这样吧，我先走，在家等你
That's all
就这么说定了
Ping
炳，炳
Mr.Chow, is Mr.Koo in?
周先生，顾先生在不在？
He's out, forgot to buy the paper again?
他出去了，又忘了买报纸了?
That's right, I'll stop by later
是，我待会儿再来
Maybe I can find it for you Thank you
- 我帮你找找看 - 谢谢你
This one? Yes
- 是这一张吗？ - 是的
I always loved those serials, hated to miss an episode
我以前也常看的，一天不看就不自在
Really? You like them too?
是吗？你也喜欢看武侠小说？
I even thought of writing one
迷过一阵子，我还想过自己写
Why didn't you?
为什么没写
I couldn't get started, so I gave up
想来想去开不了头，也就算了
I wasn't born to write martial arts stories
注定不是干这一行的
But you can borrow from my collection any time
那些武侠小说我都留着，要看你拿去
Not now, maybe another time, thanks
不了，下回再麻烦你，谢谢你
You're welcome
不客气
What is it, Mrs. Chan?
什么事，陈太太？
I just want to return these to Mr.Chow is he in?
这些书还给周先生的，他在不在家？
He's been away for a few days
他好几天没回来
Why?
怎么回事？
They had a quarrel
两夫妻吵架了
Leave them with me
你把书搁下吧，等周先生回来
I'll pass them back to him
我帮你还给他
Thank you
谢谢
Forget it
不用了
I'm on a replacement shift tonight
今晚我值夜班
Talk to you later
你先回去吧
No need to pick me up
再说吧，今晚我会迟一点， 你不用来接我了
She's already left
她已经走啦
Really? I was going to take her out for supper
是吗，还想接她一块吃夜宵
Didn't she tell you she was off early today
她没告诉你吗？她今天早下班
She never remembers to tell me
她老是这样，颠三倒四的
Maybe she's home by now
说不定已经回到家里了
I'll be off, then
那我先走了
Okay, bye
好的，再见
Hello
你好
You're out of hospital
你出院了吗？
Don't mention hospital, Lend me $30
先别说了，借我三十块
What for?
干什么？
You gotta help me save face
帮帮忙，名誉攸关
What's the big deal?
出了什么大事？
It's Ah Hoi's fault
还不是那个阿海，那天来医院看我
He gave me a racing tip, said it was a sure thing
说有内幕消息，稳赢的
Before they'd taken out the stitches
我看他那么有把握，线都来不及拆
I rushed from hospital to Race Course
一股劲跑出医院，赶去马场
I bet everything I had
把老婆本都押上了
and I lost my shirt
结果输了个精光
What did you expect?
活该，刚开完刀还要去赌
I thought it was my lucky day
我想负伤上阵，必有大运
Anyhow, I had only $2 left
谁知输剩两块钱
So I went to the whorehouse
赌气就跑去找贵妃
You were in no shape for sex
病到这样子你还要去玩女人啊？
I thought it would improve for sex
想冲冲喜嘛
What would $2 buy you?
不是只剩两块钱？够吗？
I'm Kwai Fei's regular, she gives me credit
我是常客，好商量，先赊着也可以的
You can have in on credit?
这种事情也可以赊账？
I left my ID card and
把身份证押给她
said I'd be back to redeem it
说好两三天后回去拿
I thought a few dollars would be back easy to rustle up
原以为这么一点钱很容易
But so far nothing I'm way overdue
谁知到现在还没搞定，还过了期
So?
那怎办？
Four Eyes was there yesterday
怎办？昨儿小四上去
Saw her waving my ID around in
可不就看见她拿着我那张身份证
front of everyone
到处让人看
So embarrassing
你说衰不衰啊？
Anyway, lend me $30
先别说了，给我三十块
This is all can spare
我只有那么多
I need $10 for myself
留十块，这些你拿去用
Pay you back next month
月初就还你
Let's have a late snack What?
- 去吃宵夜 - 还要吃宵夜？
All I've had today is some won-ton noodles
一整天就吃了一碗云吞面，都快饿死了
Let me finish writing this first
等我写好这一段吧
I'm not sure I should tell you this
有件事，我不知道要不要跟你说
What?
什么事？
I saw your wife in the street yesterday
昨天在街上看见你老婆
So what?
这有什么好奇怪的？
That is nothing
奇怪倒不奇怪
but she was with some guy
不过她好像跟一个男人走在一起
Probably a friend
可能是她朋友
Just thought you should know
说得也对，我不过是随便说说而已
Miss Yu? This is me
余小姐吗，我是苏秘书啊
Mr.Ho's still in a meeting
何先生还在谈事情
he says he can't manage dinner
他说晚上恐怕不能跟你吃饭
Yes, we're very busy now
是，我们这阵子很忙
I'll, I'll ask Mr.Ho to call
好的，我会跟他说，再见
Have you called Miss Yu? Yes, I've
- 你跟余小姐说了没有？ - 说过了
What did she say?
她怎么说？
Asks you to call her later
她叫你晚一点给她电话
And Mrs. Ho says she's ready to cut her birthday cake
何太太来过电话，说快切蛋糕了
She wants you to hurry home
叫你快回去
Did you get me something to give her? Yes, this
- 礼物买了没有？ - 买了
What is it? A scarf
- 是什么东西？ - 是围巾
I think Mrs. Ho will like it Thank you
- 我想何太太会喜欢吧 - 麻烦你了
And here's your change
用剩的钱
I'm always troubling you
不用了，你拿着，老是麻烦你
use it for bus fare
车费也要的
Why don't you dine with us tonight?
不如，到我家吃顿便饭？
Thank you, I've already planned to see a film tonight
别客气，我约了我先生看电影
Then I won't keep you
那就不妨碍你们了
Tomorrow will be quiet
明天上午没什么事
take the morning off
你可以下午才回来
Goodbye goodbye
- 再见 - 再见
Are you going out tonight?
你今天晚上会出去吗？
Don't forget your keys
记得拿钥匙
All the neighbors are dining out tonight
孙太太他们去吃喜酒
I have a lot to do here so I'll be late
公司很忙，我会晚点回来
What is it, Mrs. Chan?
什么事，陈太太
I heard voices
我听见隔壁有声音
I thought Mr.& Mrs. Koo were back
还以为是顾先生顾太太回来
Not yet, anything I can help with?
还没有，你找他们有事？
No, I just wanted a chat
没什么，找他们聊聊天
Are you alone? Yes, I am
- 你一个人？ - 是
You're back early today
这么早回来？
I'm not feeling well, I came back to rest
有点不舒服，就早点回来了
What is it? I have some medicines
你哪里不舒服，我有药
Don't trouble yourself, I'll sleep it off
不用了，我睡会儿就好
In that case, I'll leave you in peace
好，我不打扰了
It was your wife
你的老婆
Have you spoken to your wife yet?
跟你老婆说了没有？
Then we shouldn't meet any more
那么你以后别再找我
Any news from the Philippines?
菲律宾那边有没有消息
Yes, a telex
刚收到电报
There's a typhoon, so the ship's still docked
说那边刮台风，船都不能开
Please inform Chan
那么你马上通知陈先生
That the shipment may be delayed
说他那批货可能要晚一两天才能到
Ask if that's a problem
问他有没有问题
Your wife rang
何太太打过电话来
you don't need to pick her up
说用不着回家去接她
She's playing mahjong with Mrs. Lau
她在跟刘太太打牌
She'll meet you at the restaurant at 5:30
你五点半直接上天香楼找她便行
and there's a gift from Miss Yu
余小姐有一份礼物交给你
She was here?
她上来过？
No, she had it sent over
不，她找人送上来的
She says she'll dine alone since it's your birthday
她说知道你今天生日，应酬多
Please phone her
所以不找你吃饭了
when you have a moment
叫你有空再给她电话
I'll get you another coffee Thank you
- 我帮你倒杯咖啡 - 谢谢
Thank you
谢谢
That tie looks good on you
领带很漂亮
You noticed?
你看得出我换了领带吗？
It's much like the old one
我还以为差不多
You notice things if you pay attention
仔细看能看出来
I'll be off now
我先走了
If Chan has a problem
如果陈先生那边有问题
let me know at the restaurant
打电话到天香楼找我
Why did you change your tie?
怎么把领带又换了？
The new one was too showy
我嫌那条太花俏了点儿
I should stick with my own
还是换回原来的好
Don't forget to lock up
记得锁门啊
By the way, haven't seen your husband lately
对了，最近很少看见你先生
He's abroad now, on company business
是呀，这阵子他公司有事，派了他出去
That's why I see you at the noodle stall
怪不得老在面摊碰见你
I don't like cooking for myself
一个人懒得煮饭
Haven't seen your wife lately either
对了，你太太呢？最近也很少看见她
Her mother's ill, she's at home with her
她妈妈身体不太舒服，回娘家陪陪她
That explains it
难怪了
Good night Good night
- 晚安 - 晚安
Mrs. Chan, I'm glad you're back
陈太太，你回来就好了
It's raining so hard
外面雨下得那么凶
I was going to look for you with and umbrella
我还想打伞去接你呢
You are too kind
不过是阵头雨，你有心
Amah, who is it?
王妈，是谁？
It's Mrs. Chan
是陈太太
Mrs. Suen
孙太太
Caught in the rain? I said you could
哎呀，下那么大雨还出去呀
eat with us
大家自己人，早叫你一道吃
Next time, Enjoy your game
下回吧，慢慢打
Her husband's always away
哎呀，她先生一天到晚在外头
It's sad to see her to lonely
她一个人孤伶伶怪可怜的
She dresses up like that to go out for noodle
出去买碗面，还穿得真漂亮
Mr.Chow, What are you doing here?
周先生，怎么到这边来了？
Just calling Mrs. Koo to the phone
我过来叫顾太太听电话
You're late back
这么晚？
I went to the picture
刚看了场电影
I'll be going
我先回去了
Hello
喂
Yes, please hold on
啊，你等等啊
Who is it? It's for Mrs. Chan
- 是谁的电话？ - 陈太太的电话
It must seem odd to ask you out but I want to ask something
那么冒昧约你出来，是有点事想请教你
That handbag I saw you with this evening
你今天下午拿着的皮包
Where did you buy it?
不知道哪里有的买？
Why do you ask?
你为什么这样问？
It looked so elegant
哦，我看款式很别致
I want to get one for my wife
想买一个送给我太太
Mr.Chow, you're so good to your wife
周先生对太太真细心
Not really, my wife is so fussy
那里，她这人很挑剔
Her birthday is two days away
过两天她生日
I don't know what to get her
不知道买什么送给她才好
Could you buy one for me to give her?
你可不可以帮我买一个？
Maybe she wouldn't want one just exactly the same
要是一模一样的，她会不喜欢吧
You're right, I didn't think of that
说的也是，我倒也没想到
Women would mind
女人会介意，对吧？
Yes, especially since we're neighbors
会的，特别是隔壁邻居
Do they come in other colors?
不知道会不会有别的颜色
I'd have to ask my husband
那要问我先生才知道
Why?
为什么？
He bought it for me
那皮包是我先生
on a business trip abroad
在外地工作的时候买给我的
They aren't on sale here
他说在香港没有卖的
Then never mind
那就算了吧
Actually
其实
I want to ask your something too
我也有一件事情想请教你
What?
什么事？
Where did you buy your tie?
你的领带在哪里买的？
I don't know where it came from
我还真的不知道
My wife buys all my ties
我领带全是我太太帮我买的
Really?
是吗？
She bought this one
我想起来了，有一次她公司派她出去
on a business trip abroad
回来送给我的
It's not on sale here
她说香港没有卖的
What a coincidence
倒有这么巧
Yes
是啊
Actually
其实
My husband has one just like it
我先生也有条领带跟你的一模一样
He said it was a gift from his boss
他说是他老板送他的
So he wears it every day
所以天天戴着
Any my wife has a bag just like yours
我太太也有个皮包跟你那个一模一样
I know, I have seen it
我知道，我见过
What are you getting at, actually?
你想说什么
I thought I was the only one who knew
我还以为只有我一个人知道
I wonder how it began
不知道他们是怎样开始的
It's late, won't your wife complain?
你这么晚不回家，你老婆不说你吗？
She's used to it, she doesn't care
早习惯了，她不管我的
And your husband?
你呢？你老公不说什么吗？
He must be asleep by now
我想他早睡了
Shall we stay out tonight?
今晚别回去了
My husband would never say that
我老公不会这样讲的
What would he say?
他会怎么讲
Anyhow, he wouldn't say that
就是不会讲
Someone must have made the first move
总有一个人先开口吧
Who else could it be?
不是他是谁？
It's late, won't your wife complain?
你这么晚不回家，你老婆不会问吗？
She's used to it, she doesn't care
早习惯了，她不管的
And your husband?
你老公不会说什么吗？
He must be asleep by now
我想他早睡了
I can't say it
我真的说不出口
I understand
我明白
After all, it's already happened
事到如今
It doesn't matter who made the first move
谁先开口有什么所谓
Do you really know your wife?
其实你知不知道你老婆是怎样的人
You order for me
你帮我点
Why?
为什么？
I've no idea what your wife likes
我想知道你老婆喜欢吃什么
What about your husband?
那么你丈夫喜欢吃什么
Like it hot?
吃得惯吗？
Your wife likes hot dishes
你老婆挺能吃辣的
Why did you call me at the office today?
为什么打电话到我公司？
I had nothing to do, I want to hear your voice
没事做，想听听你的声音
You have my husband down pat
学得倒挺像我老公
He's real sweet-talker
油嘴滑舌
Why didn't you call me today?
你为什么不打电话给我？
I was afraid you won't like it
怕你会不高兴
Then don't call me again
那么以后不要再打电话给我
Mrs. Chan, a letter from your husband
陈太太，陈先生有封信来了，你看看
It's not for me, it's for Mr.Chow next door
不是我的，是隔壁周先生的
The Japanese stamp made me think
我看见信封上的日本邮票
it was your husband
以为是陈先生寄来
So I was wrong
原来不是
Your wife's in Japan?
你老婆去了日本？
How did you know?
你怎么知道
What did she say in her letter?
信里写些什么？
Nothing special
没什么
Anything about when she'd be back?
有没有说几时回来？
No
没有
What do you think they're doing right now?
你猜他们现在在做什么？
Are you alright? I'm fine
- 你没事吧？ - 没事
Please pull up here
麻烦你在前面停停车
Why?
干什么？
I'll get off first
我先下车
No, let me
不好，我先下
Mrs. Chan Ah Ping, you're back
- 陈太太 - 炳哥，你回来了？
Visiting Mr.Chow?
- 是啊 - 找周先生？
Yes, I thought we'd have lunch but he isn't well
想找他喝茶，哪知道他病了
What's wrong with him?
怎么回事？
He's got fever, he's all alone
发烧，他老婆又不在家
So I'm gonna buy him something to eat
一个人怪可怜的，下去给他买点什么吃
The congee downstairs is quite good
街口那家店，卖的粥挺好的
He doesn't want congee
他不想吃粥
What does he want?
他想吃什么
Can't taste anything, so he wants sesame syrup
他说嘴里淡得慌，想吃芝麻糊
Damned troublesome
真难缠
Amah
王妈，王妈
Mrs. Suen, she's hanging the washing on the roof
孙太太，王妈上天台晾衣服去了
You're back
你回来了
Yes, you've been out?
这是刚上街回来？
My mother's birthday is coming up
是呀，下礼拜我妈过生日
So I took her to buy some fabric
我带她去买点布料做新衣
It took all day, I'm half dead
跑了一整天，气都喘不上来了
And I had my hair done, is it nice?
顺道烫了个头发，好看吗？
Very nice
很漂亮
What are you cooking?
你在煮什么？
I had a sudden craving for sesame syrup
忽然想吃芝麻糊
That whole pot is for you
一大锅你怎么吃呀
I thought I might as well make a potful
反正煮了，大家一块吃吧
You're so thoughtful
你真客气
Please try it I'll
- 来一碗吧 - 好啊
What a coincidence
这么巧
Going out?
是啊，上街吗？
I'll buy some noodles, I'm starving
整晚没吃过东西了，下来吃碗面
Hungary? Will you join me?
你饿不饿？一起啊？
No thanks
不了
Just off work?
这么晚才下班？
You must be very busy
公司很忙？
Actually, I've been to see a picture
就是没事做，所以看了场电影
Really? How was it?
是吗，好不好看？
So-so
马马虎虎
I used to like going to the pictures
我从前也爱看电影
You had many hobbies before
你以前倒是挺多嗜好的
On your own, you are free to do lots of things
自己一个人，大把时间， 想做什么就做什么
Everything changes when you marry
结了婚就不一样
It must be decided together
很多事情，一个人作不了主
Right?
对不对？
I sometimes wonder what I'd be
有时候我会想，要是现在还没有结婚
if I hadn't married
不知会怎样
Have you ever thought of that?
你也会这样想吗？
Maybe happier
可能会比较开心吧
I didn't know married life would be
我以前都没有想到婚姻
so complicated
是这样复杂
When you're single, you are only responsible to yourself
如果一个人，自己做得好就够了
Once you're married
可是当两个人在一起时
doing well on your own is not enough
只有自己做得好是不够的
Don't brood on it, maybe he'll be back soon
别想太多了，等他们回来再说吧
What about you?
你没事啊？
Actually, we're in the same boat
其实我跟你还不是一样
But I don't brood on it
我只是不去想
It's not my fault
又不是我做错
I can't waste time wondering if I made mistakes
何必每天问自己做错了什么
Life's too short for that
浪费自己时间
Something must change
我不想这样下去
So what's your plan?
你有什么打算？
I want to write a martial-arts
这几天我躺在床上翻武侠小说
serial...
我想再写
Actually, I've started one, I'll show it to you
已经开了头，过两天让你看
Great
好啊
You like them too
你这么喜欢看武侠小说
so why not help me write it?
我们一起写吧
I wouldn't know how, I only read them
这怎么行，我只会看，哪里会写
We would discuss it together
试试看嘛
Alright, I'll try my best
那好吧，我尽量
I never thanked you for the sesame syrup
还没多谢你的芝麻糊呢
There's no need I was making it anyway
别客气，小意思嘛
Amazing, I was craving for some
说起来真巧
sesame syrup that day
刚好那天我很想吃芝麻糊
Really? What's a coincidence
是吗，这么巧
It really was
是呀，就这么巧
I'll go for those noodles
我先去吃点东西
Again, halfway through dinner, he's drunk
老是这样子，酒席吃到一半就醉倒
Disgusting
真讨厌
- I told you to stop - What can you do?
- 早说别给他喝了 - 我有啥办法
It's me
是我
You scared me
吓死我了
How's Mr.Koo?
怎样？顾先生有没有事？
Drunk, as usual
喝醉了吧
I didn't expect them back so early
怎会这样早
Since you're trapped here, finish the noodles
反正没法子，不如先把面吃完再说
They'll probably go soon
我想他们坐一会儿就走
Want some soup?
加点汤吗？
要不要加点汤？
Mrs. Suen, playing here tonight
孙太太，怎么在这边打麻将？
Yes, Mrs. Koo is dealing with her husband
顾太太说要看着她先生嘛
I could do that
早跟我说嘛，我来照顾他就行了
No, we should not trouble you
怎好意思呀
Think you'll play all night?
这样高兴，看来要玩到天亮
No, we'll just play eight rounds
才不会，顶多八圈
They'll play till morning?
你猜他们会不会打到天亮？
Mrs. Suen says only eight rounds
孙太太说只打八圈
You believe that?
你信不信？
You get some rest, I'll wake you when they leave
不如你瞌睡一会，他们散了我就叫你
And you?
那你呢？
I have a chapter to finish
我先把这段写好
Where have you got to?
写到哪儿？
The drunken master just showed up
大醉侠出场
When did he get written in?
怎么多了个大醉侠？
Just now
刚想到的
Mr.Chow, home so early?
周先生，这样早就出去啊
I went out to buy some food
我下去买点吃的
No work today?
你今天不用上班吗？
I didn't feel so good, I'm staying home
有点不太舒服，告了一天假
A sick man shouldn't eat all that sticky rice
不舒服还吃这么多糯米鸡
Some of it's for later
省得晚上再出去买
Don't stuff yourself
当心吃撑了
Good morning
周先生
Good morning, finished your game?
你早，散场了吗，孙太太？
Not yet, but Mr.Yang has to work
没有呢，杨先生要办公，让他先走了
Mr.Tsai is coming to replace him
不过蔡先生马上就来
Did you call the office for me?
有没有帮我打电话回公司请假？
Yes
打过了
What did you tell them?
你怎么说的
That you weren't feeling well
说你病了
Did them ask who you were?
他们有没有问你是谁
No
没有
Probably took me for your husband
多半以为我是你丈夫吧
Mr.Ho knows that he's away
何先生知道他出门了
Pretend he's come back
就说他已经回来好了
Maybe we're being too cautious?
都是自己吓自己
I'm always round anyway
平日我也常过来
We shouldn't have panicked
有什么好紧张的
Well, they did turn up without warning
这很难说，他们突然之间回来
What would they assume?
不知道他们会怎么乱想
We can't put a foot wrong
所以真的不能走错一步
You can go
走吧
Amah Mrs. Chan, you're back very late
- 王妈 - 陈太太，怎么这样晚？
I had a lot of work today
是呀，今天公司事情多
I didn't see you leave this morning
怎么今早没看见你上班？
I had breakfast with my mother
今天很早约了妈妈喝茶
You weren't here when I left
我出去的时候你还没来
Where's Mrs. Suen?
孙太太呢？
Asleep, she played mahjong all day
她搓麻将搓到天亮，才刚睡
Be quiet, don't wake her Alright
- 别吵她了 - 好的
Mrs. Chan, is your leg alright?
呀，陈太太，你的脚还好吧
It's these new shoes
没什么，新鞋子太窄，挤脚了
Why a special dinner tonight?
干嘛请我吃饭？
Since you won't take your share of
今天出稿费，你那一份你又不收
the writing fee
只好请你吃饭了
None of my business
其实不关我的事
All I did was give you some thoughts
我在旁边打打边鼓而已
Someone else is asking for a serial too
我也许会多写一家报纸
There'll be more work soon
今天有人打电话来约稿
Really? So quickly
是吗？那太好了
Isn't the workload too much?
你应付得了吗？
That's why I'm looking for a new place
所以想找一个地方
What for?
做什么？
To write in
写东西
lt'll be more convenient
这样你以后上来都方便点嘛
There's nothing between us
虽然我们之间没什么
but I don't want gossip
但是我不想别人误会你
What do you think?
你觉得怎样？
Why waste money?
太浪费了
You don't need me
其实都是你自己写的
you can write on your own
何必多此一举呢
Who do you want?
喂，找谁呀？
Chow Mo-Wan?
周慕云？
He hasn't been in for several days
他没上班好几天了
We're looking for him too
我们也到处在找他
May I know who's calling?
你是哪位啊？
Any message?
要留个话吗？
It's no trouble, goodbye
哦，不用谢，多挂来啊
Please get this to Accounts
这文件马上送去会计部
And have the air-conditioner serviced tomorrow
还有，冷气机明天叫人来看看
Mr.Ho
好，何先生
No need to stay if everything's done
没什么事了，你可以走了
I'll lock up Yes
- 门我来锁喽 - 好的
Hello?
喂
Where are you?
你在哪里啊？
I'll come again tomorrow
我明天再来看你
No need, I'll be alright after some rest
我歇两天就没事
It's no trouble
不要紧，才一会儿功夫
I'll bring you some food, what would you like?
我给你买点吃的，你想吃什么
Whatever
随便
Then I'll leave now, get some rest
那我就走了，你早点休息
Call me when you get home
回去给我个电话
Let it ring three times then hang up
用不着说话，响三声就好
Alright
好
I didn't think you'd come
我没想过你会来
We won't be like them
我们不会跟他们一样的
See you tomorrow
明天见
Tell me honestly
你老实告诉我
Do you have a mistress?
你外面是不是有个女人？
You're crazy
神经病
Who told you I had?
谁跟你说的
Never mind who
你别管
Do you or don't you?
你是不是有了个女人
No
没有
Don't lie
不要骗我
Look at me
你看着我，你看着我
I'm asking you, do you have a mistress
我问你，你外面是不是有个女人？
Yes
是
That's no reaction
你怎么了？
If he admits it outright
他已经承认在外面有个女人
let him have it
你还打得这么轻
I wasn't expecting he would admit it so easily
我没想到他会回答得这样干脆
I didn't know how to react
我不知道该怎么办
One more time, alright?
再来一次吧
Tell me frankly
你老实回答我
Do you have a mistress?
你外面是不是有个女人？
You're crazy
神经病
Who told you that?
谁跟你说的？
Never mind that, do you or don't you?
你别管，你是不是有个女人？
No
没有
Don't lie
你不要骗我
Tell me
你告诉我
Look at me, do you have a mistress?
你看着我，是不是有个女人？
Yes
是
Are you alright?
你没事吧
I didn't expect it to hurt so much
我没想到真的会这样伤心
This is just a rehearsal
我试试而已，又不是真的
He won't really admit it so readily
就算是真的他也不会认
It's alright, don't take it so hard
没事的，别这样
You've been out a lot lately
你最近好像应酬挺多的？
Yes
是啊
It's right to enjoy yourself while you're young
年纪轻呢，出去散散心是应该的
But don't overdo it
不过得有分寸
When will your husband be back?
你先生几时回来？
Soon
他快回来了
In future, don't let him travel so much
等他回来呢，别再让他老出门
A couple should spend time together
两夫妻经常分开呢，总不大好
Don't you agree?
你说对吗？
Good night
晚安
Will you come over tonight?
你今天晚上过不过来？
What for?
做什么？
The editor's hounding me, he says I'm too slow
这两天给催稿，说我写得慢
I need your help, when can you come?
过来帮忙手啊？你几点可以？
Not anytime soon
我想这阵子我不过来了
Why not?
怎么了？
Mrs. Suen lectured me last night
昨晚回家，让孙太太说了几句
What did he say?
她说你什么
Rather not say
我不想讲
We shouldn't see so much of each other
反正这阵子我们还是少点见面吧
Mrs. Chan, going out for noodles again?
陈太太，又要去买面啊？
Not tonight, I'll make myself something
今天不去了
Join us, we're having vegetable won-tons
随便弄点什么吃的就算了
Alright
那好的
- No lunch today, Mr.Ho? - No
- 何先生没出去吃午饭？ - 没有
Now one Mr.Zhou call you
刚才有位周先生打电话找你
He wants you to call him back
叫你回电话给他
Thank you
谢谢
- Back from work? - Yes
- 下班啦？ - 是呀
- Strange weather Isn't it - Yes
- 这真是大雨呀 - 是呀
Been here long?
在这儿站很久了？
Just a while
一会儿罢了
I don't think it'll stop soon
我想还得下好一会儿
Wait for me
你等等我
I'll see you home
我送你回去
We'd better not be seen together
让人看见，又话多了
Then you go first
那么你先回去
If they see your umbrella
他们认得你的伞
They'll know I was with you
我撑着回去，不也一样？
I wasn't thinking
这也是，我倒没想到
You go first, I'll wait a while
你先回去吧，我待一会儿就回
I'll keep you company
我陪你
Did you try to call me?
你找过我？
I wasn't sure you got the message
还以为你同事忘了告诉你
Could you get me a boat ticker?
想找你买张船票
To where?
你要去别的地方？
Ah Ping wrote from Singapore
阿炳来过很多信
They're short of staff, he'd like me to go and help
说那边缺人手，要我去帮他忙
How long will you stay?
打算去多久？
Don't know, I'll play it be ear
不知道，去了再说吧
Why rush off to Singapore?
怎么突然会想去新加坡？
A change of scene...
想换―下环境
I've had enough of the gossip
免得听着太多的闲言闲语
We know it's not true, so why worry?
我们自己知道我们没什么不就行了
I used to think that too
原来我也这样想
and it didn't worry me
所以不怕别人说闲话
I thought we wouldn't be like them
我相信我自己不会像他们那样
But I was wrong
原来会的
You won't leave your husband
我知道你不会离开你丈夫
So I'd rather go away
我想离开一下
I didn't think you'd fall in love with me
我没有想过你真的会喜欢我
I didn't either
我也没有想过
I was only curious to know how it started
我一直在想，他们是怎样开始的
Now I know
现在我明白了
Feelings can creep up just like that
原来很多事情都这样
I thought I was in control
我还以为自己没有什么
But I hate to think of our husband coming home
但是开始担心你丈夫几时会回来
I wish he'd stay away
最好不要回来
I'm so bad
我知道这样想不对
Will you do me one favour?
你能不能帮我一个忙
What?
做什么？
I want to be prepared
我想有点心理准备
You'd better not see me again
以后不要再找我了
Is your husband back?
你老公他回来了？
Yes
是啊
Am I hopeless?
我真没用
Not really
不是啊
I won't see you again
我不会再找你了
Keep a closer eye on your husband
好好地守着你的丈夫
Please
别这样
Don't be serious it's only a rehearsal
说了试着的嘛
Don't cry
别哭
This isn't real
这又不是真的
I don't want to go home tonight
我今天晚上不想回家
Mei-Yi wants to dedicate a song
陈美仪点给好朋友权仔和文文
to her honeymooning friends
祝他们成功
And Mrs. Cheung wishes the best to
又点给同屋的张太太收听
her neighbors
祝家庭幸福
And Mr.Chan, now on business in Japan
有一位在日本公干的陈先生
wants to wish his wife
点这首歌给他太太
a happy birthday
祝她生日快乐，工作顺利
So let's all enjoy Zhou Xuan singing
现在请大家一起欣赏，周璇唱的
In Full Bloom
花样的年华
It's me
是我
If there's an extra ticket
如果有多一张船票
Would you go with me?
你会不会跟我一起走？
It's me
是我
If there's an extra ticket
如果有多一张船票
Would you go with me?
你会不会带我一起走？
Mr.Chow has gone to work
哈罗？周先生不在，他上班去了
Any message?
有话要转达吗？
You're welcome
不用谢，拜拜
Has anyone been in my room?
是不是有人进过我房间？
No
没有呀
Something's missing
没有？我丢了东西
What?
丢了什么呀
In the old days
你知不知道，从前的人
If someone had a secret they didn't want to share
要是心里有了秘密，不想别人知道
You know what they did?
你知不知道他们会怎样做？
Have no idea
我怎么知道？
They went up to a mountain, found a tree
他们会跑到山上找一棵树
Carved a hole in it
在树上挖个洞
And whispered the secret into the hole
然后把秘密全说进去
Then they covered it with mud
再用泥巴封起来
And leave the secret there forever
那秘密就永远留在那棵树里，没人知道
What a pain, I'd just go to get laid
这样辛苦，找个女人发泄一下不更好
Not everyone's like you
谁都像你呀
I'm just an average guy
说得是呀，像我这样的人
I don't have secrets like you
是个直肠子，哪来的心事呀？
You bottle things up
你可不同，什么都往心里搁
Tell me something
说来听听嘛
I don't have secrets
我哪有心事
Come off it, buddy
你别瞒我啦，一场朋友
I won't tell anyone
我不会跟别人说的
Hello, Singapore Daily
喂，你好，星洲日报
Hold on
请等等
Mr.Chow, call for you
云哥，电话
Thanks
谢谢
Hello
喂
- Who is it? - It is me
- 谁呀？ - 王妈，是我啊
- Mrs. Chan, long time no see - Yes
- 陈太太，好久没见了 - 是呀
- Amah, who's there? - Mrs. Suen
- 王妈，什么人呀 - 孙太太
What brings you here?
哎呀，你怎么会过来啊？
It's been a while
我想这么久没来看你
I was nearby
今天刚好来这附近
so I thought I'd bring your boat ticket
特意把船票给你送来
And a small gift
请你吃的
You shouldn't have, it's nice just to see you
哎呀，上来坐坐就好了， 还这样客气，又破费
The place is in such a mess
你看这屋里乱七八糟的
Already started packing?
你已经在收拾了？
It's hopeless,
已经收拾好几天了
I can't bear to throw things away
东西太多，有些又舍不得扔
- Let's find you a seat - OK
- 坐的地方都没有，到这边坐 - 好啊
- Have some tea - Thank you
- 吃茶 - 谢谢，王妈
Eat with us, Mrs. Chan, I'm going to the market
你今天别走，在这里吃晚饭，我去买菜
I can't, I have work waiting
不行呢，我还得回公司办点事
Don't rush off
你干嘛急着走
if you don't eat here
你不留在这儿吃饭
Mrs. Suen will be upset
太太要不高兴的，太太？
Amah, pour me some tea too
嗳，你替我倒杯茶来
How's your husband?
陈先生好吗？
He's fine, thank you
挺好的，有心了
How long will you be away?
你打算走多久？
I don't know
我也不晓得
If I like it, I might stay
要是住的惯呢我就不回来了
Why?
为什么？
My daughter worries about the situation in Hong Kong
我女儿说现在香港这么乱
She worry about I stay alone in Hong Kong
我自己一个人在这边她不放心
I don't want to leave
我倒是舍不得离开香港的
Since the Koos left
不过自从顾先生他们搬走了以后
I don't have my mahjong partners anymore
搓麻将也没搭伴
And my daughter needs help with her kids in the US
想想呢，还是到美国去给女儿带孩子算了
What about this place?
这房子怎么办？
I'm not sure
正为了这个伤脑筋嘛
I don't want to sell it
卖出去呢真不舍得
So I might rent it out
想想还是租给人家吧
How much would you want?
你打算租多少钱？
You're interested?
嗳？你有意思租吗？
You could have it at a discount
租给你我可就放心了， 我便宜点租给你啦
I'll think about it
我想想看
Mrs. Suen, your tea
太太，吃茶
Who lives next door now?
对了，现在是什么人住在隔壁？
I don't really know them
我也不大晓得，不像以前，都没往来
The Koos were almost like family
以前跟顾先生顾太太不知多热闹
It was so nice then
像一家人一样，想起来也开心
wasn't it?
你说是吗？
Yes
是啊
Let's sit over here
过来这边坐
Yes?
你找哪位？
Is Mr.Koo in?
请问顾先生在不在？
He moved long ago
顾先生？搬了好久了
Do you know where he is?
知不知道搬到哪儿去了？
You know him well?
你跟他很熟吗？
I used to live here
我从前住在这里
Is Mrs. Suen still next door?
孙太太还住在隔壁吗？
She's gone, it's too chaotic
也搬了，现在乱成这样
Everyone's running away
能走的还不走吗？
So who lives there now?
现在隔壁住着什么人？
I am not sure
我也不太清楚
A woman and her son
好像就是一个女人带着她儿子
The kid is cute
那小孩子蛮可爱的
No address in the Philippines
他菲律宾的地址我没找着
Just his son's phone number
只有他儿子的电话
- I can't accept this - How this
- 你拿回去 - 这怎行
Please, you must
小意思，不客气
- Thank you, then - Bye
- 那么谢谢了 - 慢走
That era has passed
那个时代已过去
Nothing that belonged to
属于那个时代的一切
it exists any more
都不存在了
Are you ready?
庸生，好了没？
- Okay - Let's go
- 好了 - 快点
The presidential corps waits at Pochentong Airport
柬埔寨首都机场上
Prince Norodom Sihanouk and Queen sisowath Kossamak
皇室人员上前
come forward to greet General De Gaulle
迎接戴高乐将军
It's ten kilometres from Pochentong to Phnom Penh
公路上列队欢迎
200,000 people line the route
人潮达二十万人
A welcome unprecedented in the history of the Kingdom
写下该国前所未有的一页